Elijah Raffo

8099 SW Woody End St. Portland, OR 97224

- (971) 275-7057
- eliraffo@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/eliraffo
- eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An operations and business analyst with a passion for utilizing information to create and implement impactful solutions. Completed analytic projects in business operations, large datasets, automation, and measuring key performance indicators. Has experienced working within in a fast-paced environment, building a team, learning complex business systems, communicating complex concepts, being a self-starter, and problem solving.

EDUCATION

University of Oregon • Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Major Concentration • Operations and Business Analytics

Minor

■ Computer Information Technology

Relevant Coursework: Supply Chain Operations and Management ● Business Strategy and Planning ● Predictive Analytics ● Database Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst (Part-time)

Lane Forest Products, Inc. ● Eugene, OR

June 2018 - Current

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

General Responsibilities:

Answered stakeholder questions by performing database queries, data analysis, and data visualization to present useful information.

Reported on how and why profit per ton and total outbound tonnage change for material sent to Kingsford

Improved functional areas by redesigning spreadsheets and/or introducing new procedures.

Implemented quality control procedures for a \$25,000 piece of equipment in the Wood Recycling department

Operated as the inventory control specialist of a logistic reload which over 6 months moved over 55,000 tons of material.

- Managed relationships with stakeholders by reporting measured inventory and measuring percentage of material lost
- Partnered with the database manager to perform an ETL procedure which automated the reconciliation of information.

Operated as the export specialist for international orders by managing documentation, accounts payable/receivable, and movement of materials.

Created Project flowcharts and procedures to simplify and scale the international export of material.

Analytic Projects:

Conducted an analysis of the Delivery Department by quantitatively measuring costs and modeling possible profit/loss combinations which resulted. in a proposed pricing structure that is estimated to increase department annual profit by \$36,000.

- Created Visual models which were presented to Department Heads which intuitively displayed ~50,000 Profit/Loss combinations.
- Developed an automated delivery price spreadsheet which is being tested for implementation in the Delivery Department.

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company ◆ Portland, OR

June 2017 – September 2017

Implemented a redesigned Point-of-Sale interface at all Eugene Teahouse locations which resulted in:

- Data that can be used to measure Key Performance Indicators and used in a Material Resource Planning system.
- A spreadsheet that Storefront managers could use to automate bi-weekly inventory tracking and reorder points.

SKILLS

Beginner * R ● * VBA ● * Macros ● Demand Forecasting ● Database Modeling ● Case Analysis ● Regression ● React ● Visio ● Access Intermediate

* Excel • * Tableau • * SQL • * Python • Data Analytics • Optimization • JavaScript • MS Suite

PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATES

Wine Using python, developed machine learning models to classify and predict the quality of a wine (up to an 85% accuracy). Presented Classification on the findings of these models, and how impact the industrial wine making process with these models.

Hershey's Built an optimization model which factors in realistic inventory and production constraints of producing a Hershey's Kiss. Reported Optimization findings of a four-week production cycle where weekly supply, demand, and carry-over inventory fluctuate.

Video Game Recorded data on video game accessories, consoles, and games. Produced an ER diagram, relational schema, and database **Database** built to the second normal form. Ran and presented queries that answer real world consumer questions.

Certificate of Outdoor Leadership

Over 3 years, attended classes on developing leadership skills and survival skills in the backcountry. Applied these lessons as an assistant leader in university classes taught by the Outdoor Pursuits Program. Experienced leading groups of six on three-day backcountry outings, teaching outdoor rock-climbing safety, and teaching vertical rescue techniques.

^{*} Improved further outside of University by enrolling in online courses or through work